Circuit of Fire
Torque is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Joseph Kahn.
Biker Cary Ford is framed by an old rival and biker gang leader for the murder of another gang member who
happens to be the brother of Trey, leader of the most feared biker gang in the country.
Ford is now on the run trying to clear his name from the murder
with Trey and his gang looking for his blood.
Ford, played by Martin Henderson.
Trey, played by Ice Cube.
Shane, played by Monet Mazur.
China, played by Jaime Pressly.
Henry James, played by Matt Schulze.
Dalton, played by Jay Hernandez.
Torque is a 2004 American action film directed by Joseph Kahn (in his feature film
directorial debut), written by Matt Johnson and produced by Neal H.
The film stars Martin Henderson, Ice Cube, Monet Mazur, Adam
Scott, Matt Schulze, Jaime Pressly, and Jay Hernandez.
Its plot follows Cary Ford, a biker discovers and stows away motorcycles filled with
crystal meth, but a gangster, Henry James, has plans to recover his drugs.
He frames Ford for the murder of his rival Trey's
brother, who heads the Reapers, a biker gang.
Ford goes on the run in an attempt to clear his name, while the FBI and
multiple groups of motorcycle-mounted marauders chase after him.
Torque was theatrically released on January 16, 2004,
in the United States by Warner Bros.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing $46.5 million worldwide against production budget of $40 million, and received mixed-to-negative
reviews from critics, with common criticisms regarding the screenplay and direction, though the action sequences were singled out for praise.
It was nominated for several Taurus Awards for its stunts.
The film explores themes of drug dealer,
corruption, ex-girlfriend, revenge, gang.
The tone is lighthearted.